you flashed legally elected I mean no
вы сверкнули законно избрано В смысле
one to overthrow you do not
никто не свергать вы не
overthrow in
свергать в
Rostov Hello Good ve where are you from I am
Ростов Здравствуйте Добрый ве откуда Я
from Volgograd And you Cool my father is
из Волгограда А вы Прикольно у меня отец
from Volgograd
родом из Волгограда
Well I am now from Ukraine I see that you are from
Ну я сейчас из Украины я вижу что вы с
Ukraine And where are you from I was born also in
Украины А вы откуда я родился тоже в
Ukraine I am from the city
Украине Я из города
you I was born in Poltava I understood how I got to
вы я в Полтаве родился понял как попали
Volgograd I
Волгоград очень
studied very hard at the institute in St. Petersburg then
тяжело учился в институте в Питере потом
by distribution I got to Volgograd I understood
по распределению попал в Волгоград понял
And how do you communicate Well naturally here
А чем общаетесь Ну естественно здесь
Politics how else
Политика как по-другому
Well let's what interests you about
ещё Ну давайте что вас интересует о
politics what is still unclear It is clear
политике что непонятно ещ Понятно
naturally I was born in
естественно я родился
Ukraine as if It is clear I live in Russia
Украине как бы Понятно живу в России
naturally I am this question Very
естественно меня этот вопрос Очень
interested in what do you think will end with the
интересует как думаете чем
collapse of the Russian Federation
закончится развалом Российской Федерации
as well as the collapse of the Russian Empire and the
так же как развалом Российской империи и
collapse of the Soviet Union well And suddenly no
развалом Советского Союза хорошо А вдруг
suddenly no you are ssi you asked
нет вдруг нет вы же сси вы же спросили
me my expert opinion and I am
меня моё экспертное мнение а я вам
telling you I am telling you what what suddenly Well
рассказываю Рассказываю что а вдруг Ну
so far there are no such that there are no such that there are no such What can there
пока вот нет
be now
таких Какие может могут быть сейчас вот
for the collapse of the Russian Empire some
для развала Российской Империи какие-то
I don't even  I know the prerequisites question question
Я даже не знаю предпосылки вопрос вопрос
And what were the prerequisites In ninety-
А какие предпосылки были В девяносто
one for the collapse of the Soviet Union Yes, I
первом для развала Советского Союза Да
agree,
согласен
okay, you can say that, and now
хорошо Вы можете такое сказать а теперь
something at least close At least something like that
что-нибудь хотя бы вот близко Хоть что
in Russia Look,
так в Рос Вот смотрите какие Скажите
what were the prerequisites that the
какие были предпосылки что распадётся
Soviet Union would collapse? It was fantastic, it was
Советский Союз это фантастика была
true, it was good, but Ukraine would collapse and
правда хорошо а Украина развалится и
Ukraine could collapse too, it could
Украина может развалиться тоже может
be like that, yeah, okay, let's wait. Well,
такое быть да Хорошо Давайте Так подожди
look. Do you agree that in order for the
Ну смотри Ты согласен что для того чтобы
Russian Federation to collapse, no
развалилась Российская Федерация не
visible prerequisites are needed for the
нужны какие-то видимые предпосылки для
Soviet Union. Everything was fine with it, too,
Советского Союза у него тоже всё хорошо
on the doi, according to plan, in short, there they were the very
было на дои по плану короче там в самые
first in space, the very first in weapons,
первые в космосе самые первые по оружию
then And it didn't
потом И не
become good. The Soviet Union didn't become good, but
стало хорошо Советский Союз не стал но
in fact it survived. No, why did
фактически он сохранился Нет почему в
Yeltsin, Kravchuk, and
Ельцин ельн Кравчук и
Shushkevich sign in Belka Pushcha? Yes, that the Soviet Union
это Шушкевич подписали Да что совей Союз
ceased to exist. It doesn't exist. It's
Прекратил своё существование его
good that Russia, the
нету хорошо Россия
Socialist Republic of Ukraine, the
Социалистической Республики Украина
Heir to the URSR, the Ukrainian Soviet
Наследник урср украинской Советской
Socialist Republic, and the Soviet
Социалистической Республики а Советского
Union is gone. It was the unification of these
Союза не стало это было объединение этих
republics. Okay, let it not be,
республик Хорошо пускай пускай не будет
let it not be. Well,  as if the
пускай не будет Ну как бы ведь
successor of the Soviet
наследником Советского
Union was the Russian Soviet Federative
Союза Российская Советская Федеративная
Republic which later became a Russian No
Республика которая потом стала рос Нет
it is not a successor no
она не есть наследником нет
well why is it a successor look the
хорошо е почему она есть насле смотрите
last one to leave the Soviet Union at all
последним из Советского Союза вообще
Kazakhstan Kazakhstan is the
вышел Казахстан Казахстан самый
last republic which is independent
последняя республика которая незави
well you know when they
хорошо Вы знаете когда
divided debts what about debts look debts and
делили долги причём долги смотри долги и
not debts this is the same Yes how they divided to whom they
не долги это такое Да как делили кому
divided also for example nuclear weapons they
делили также например оружие ядерное
divided something to Ukraine something was
делили что-то Украине что-то Казахстану
left for Kazakhstan And so on in general look
оставалось И так дальше вобще смотри у
you don't have look in order for you to be the
вас нет смотрите для того чтобы вы были
legal successor of the Soviet Union it is necessary for
правопреемником Советского Союза нужно
your official body to proclaim
чтобы ваш официальный орган провозгласил
Yes that we are the legal successor of the
Да что мы являемся правопреемником
Soviet Union you you are not the
Советского Союза у вас вы не есть
legal successor of the Soviet
правопреемником Советского
Union okay And where are the nuclear weapons then and
Союза ладно А где ядерное оружие тогда а
nuclear weapons were in Ukraine in Russia and
ядерное оружие было в Украине в России и
in Kazakhstan
в Казахстане
for free Why don't you have them
дарам Почему у вас оно его не стало
because we later as an independent
потому что мы потом как независимое
state decided to abandon them Well they
государство решили отказаться от него Ну
merged No it's just not us who decided We
слились Да нет просто не мы решили Мы
decided that in that political
решили что в той гие политической
situation it would be inadequate to maintain these nuclear weapons Yes
ситуации содержать это ядерное оружие Да
it would be inadequately expensive to service it would be
обслуживать это будет неадекватно дорого
expensive to maintain nuclear weapons nuclear violations
иго дорого содержать ядер ядерно наруш
expensive to maintain Well yes and it is necessary  somewhere to
содержать дорого Ну да и надо где-то
do tests Yes, for example, we don't have a
испытания делать Да например у нас нету
testing ground Russia, for example, has also been doing it since
полигона Россия например также уже
1991 Well, you don't
сколько с девяносто первого года Ну вы
do that modern Russia hasn't
не это не дела современная Россия не
done IR nobody does it Well, I'm saying that's all,
делала ИК его никто не делает Ну говорю
in fact, it's prohibited Okay,
вот и всё на самом деле запрещено Ладно
look And you, as you say, that
смотрите А вы же как рассказываете что у
you have the
вас
Budapest memorandum, start
будапештский меморандум начина сказки
telling fairy tales Tell me, well, in
рассказывать Скажите ну вед на самом
fact, Ukraine sort of
деле Украина как
renounced nuclear weapons not
бы отказалась ведь от ядерного оружия не
only thanks to this memorandum, it
только благодаря этому меморандуму
simply refused because it was expensive to
просто отказалась по что дорого
maintain them Do you even understand this
содержать его вы это вообще понимаете
or
или
not Russian or Belarusian someone Yes, so that
нет руского или там белорусского кто-то
you can formulate your thoughts
Да чтобы ты сформулировал свои мысли
clearly, can you formulate a question in no
чётко можешь сформулировать вопрос не
more than seven words Come on, come on,
больше чем сеь слов Давай давай так
such a well-formulated question Dava What do
хорошо сформулирован такой вопрос Дава
you
Как вы
think
считаете
Belarusian is what the Budapest
белорусски какой там будапештский
memorandum is So stop Let's do it again from the
меморандум Так стоп Давай ещё раз с
very beginning so that there are seven words Come on
самого начала чтобы сем слов было Давай
Collect your
Соберись
thoughts Budapest memorandum of
мыслями будапештский меморандум
What do you think it was Eh,
года Как вы считаете он был
so one more time, let's look like this Don't
Э так ещё раз давай так смотри Ты не
think  question and tell me this question
подумай вопрос и скажи мне этот вопрос а
otherwise you start thinking on the go how to
то ты на ходу начинаешь думать как бы
ask a question Let's do it again Pull yourself together
задать вопрос Давай ещё раз Соберись
Oh okay
Ой ладно
1994 Budapest memorandum
1994 году будапештский меморандум
which How do you think that you should have been
который Как вы считаете что вам
provided with everything wait
э должны были все обеспечить чекай
wait man Look you can take it
подожди мужик Ты смотри ты можешь
briefly Come on 10 words you don't need
коротко возьми Давай 10 слов тебе там не
seven but 10 Formulate think in your
сем а 10 Сформулируй подумай у себя в
head a question in 10 words and say it
голове вопрос на 10 слов и скажи его не
differently than you think if anything you Here
так как вы считаете если что вы Вот
briefly in 10 words question once and say
коротко на 10 слов вопрос раз и скажи
come on okay ninety-fourth year
давай хорошо девяносто четвёртый год
ward
подопечный
memorandum to you that you were obliged to
меморандум вам что обязано был
provide what security you again once again
обеспечить какую безопасность ты опять
come on 10 answer in 10 words put it
ещё раз давай 10 отве в 10 слов вложи
because you start talking
потому что ты начинаешь говорить
talking new and new words Try in
говорить новые и новые слова Попробуй в
10 words mom did they provide security or
10 слов мама обеспечили безопасность или
not Come on again 10 words 10 words question
нет Давай ещё раз 10 слов 10 слов вопрос
10 words
10 слов
put it Now
вложи Сейчас
wait something me you are trying now
подожди что-то меня ты пытаешься сейчас
I don't I want you  asked a short,
я не Я хочу чтобы ты задал короткий
succinct
ёмкий
question I ask you In ninety what year did they
вопрос я тебе задаю В девяносто чем году
provide you with security or not everything
вам обеспечили безопасность или нет всё
I asked the question everything In ninety what year no
Я задал вопрос всё В девяносто чем году
one provided us with security
нам никто не обеспечил безопасность
question By the way, you invested in your And what in
вопрос Ты кстати вложился в ше А что в
deno what year was there something with
дено чем году что-то было с
danger did they provide you with Why in deno what year
опасностью вам обеспечили Почему де году
no one pressed on us there
на нас никто не
is the Budapest memorandum
наж есть же будапештский меморандум
I want to ask about the Budapest
хоче спросить про будапештский
memorandum ask the question what was in NM
меморандум задай вопрос что было в НМ
about the Budapest memorandum in deno what no
про будапештский меморандум в дено чем
one attacked us therefore no one
на нас никто не нападал поэтому никто и
provided anything let's do it again
не обеспечивал ничего давай ещё раз
Formulate the question p Wait I have already
Сформулируй вопрос п Погоди я уже
formulated de look in dem us in deno
сформулировал де смотри в дем нам в де
what no one attacked us therefore no
чем на нас никто не нападал поэтому
one provided us with anything everything is
никто нам ничего не обеспечил всё
fine Can you formulate the question
нормально Вопрос можешь сформулировать
about Okay let's do it this way in 2004 we
про Хорошо давай так в 2004 году не
will not now about memoranda
будем сечас уже про меморандумы
so again the fourth or ryi let's start over the
так ещ раз четвёртый или рий давай начни
question in 2013  there
заново вопрос 2013
was a coup d'etat in Ukraine did
Украине произошёл
Russia respond to this or
Россия ответила на это или
not I
нет Я
ask everything there was no
спрашиваю всё в Украине не было
coup d'etat in Ukraine look at the
государственного переворота смотри бы ээ
state-elected president
государственно избранный президент
wait again look can you
подожди ещё раз смотри Можешь мне
show me a document that
показать документ в котором
records in Ukraine or for example in
зафиксировано в Украине или например в
another country that there was a
другой стороне Что в Украине произошёл
coup d'etat in Ukraine look let's start
государственный переворот смотри начнём
with the fact that there was a go again no no not
с того что в Украине был го ещё раз нене
yours can you show me a document what
не твоё можешь показать документ какой
can't a document that for example the UN
не может документ что например ООН
recognized that there was a coup d'etat
признала что государственный переворот
what the president is a state-
чём президент есть государственно
elected president once again once again
избранный президент ещё раз ещё раз ещё
look can you show me some
раз смотри Можешь мне показать какую-то
paper that there was a
бумагу что был именно переворот
state coup I tell you first
государственный Я тебе сначала говорю
no no no Look you think there
нет нет нет Смотри это ты думаешь что
was a coup And how is a
был переворот А как делается
coup d'etat done a coup d'etat comes
государственный переворот приходит
Yes the one who was
государственный переворот Да тот кого
overturned or others write Look
перевернули или другие пишут Смотрите
here he made an illegal
тут сделал незаконный государственный
coup d'etat I decree a state coup
переворот постановляю переворот
illegal he for example
государственный незаконный он например
can adopt a resolution in Ukraine there was an
может принять резолюцию в Украине прошёл
illegal Can you show me that even
незаконный Можешь мне показать что даже
Russia did not recognize that this is yes to us
Россия не признавала что это во да нам
who recognized Look Russia Russia
кто признавал Смотри Россия Россия
cooperated with the elected
сотрудничала с избранным
Poroshenko  Yes, it means it was not a coup, legally
Порошенко Да значит не переворот законно
elected, you are what you are now,
избранный вы вы какие сейчас ещё раз
look again Wait, look, if there was a coup, then
смотри Подожди смотри если был переворот
why did Russia have anything to do with Ukraine?
да то зачем Россия тогда с Украиной
Here was
что-то там имела отношение Вот был
Yanukovych legally elected, then they signed something with him.
законны Янукович тогда с ним что-то
Why do
подписывали Зачем
we need it? Show me the document that there was a coup.
нам Покажи документ что был переворот
Show the resolution on the coup. There was the
Покажи постановление о перевороте было
Verkhovna Rada. Look, there was a legally elected president.
Верховной Рады смотри был законно
Wait. Show me,
избранный президент подожди Покажи мне
not you. Now you will give me the floor.
не ты ска ты сейчас мне дашь слово скать
Come on, come on, talk. There was a legally elected
Давай давай говори был законно избранный
president. There would have been
президент был
and there was. There was, of course. That's all.
Был бы и был Был конечно был Всё Какие
What questions? And what about the
какие вопросы А причём
coup? You were also a law. You were
переворот вас у вас был тоже закон
elected president.
избраны президент
When you shone, you were legally elected. I
Когда вы сверкнули законно избрано В
mean, no one is
смысле никто не свергать вы не
overthrowing you. You are not overthrowing. They stole our president somewhere in Rostov.
свергать куда-то в Ростов украли нашего
You stole our legal
президента Вы украли нашего законного
president Yanukovych and still haven't
президента Януковича и до сих пор не
returned him. Why are you, why are you,
возвращаете Почему Вы почему Вы никакого
demanding that
президента мы до требуем вернуть до сих
he be returned. They still haven't returned him. Because we are
пор пор его его не вернули так как мы мы
leading troops to Rostov. We demanded so much.
что в Ростов войска ведём мы тре так
Look, we are demanding.  we demand yes Give
требуем смотри мы мы требуем да Отдайте
us this Yanukovych building Yes you don't
нам этого стро Януковича Да вы не
give it back you are thieves You stole our
отдаёте вы воры Вы украли нашего
president no no I am our legitimate
президента не не я наш законный
president during the time Yanukovych is not here yet
президент во время пока нету пока нету
Yes we have other presidents
Януковича Да у нас другие президенты
being elected if we return Yanukovych we will
избираются если мы вернём Януковича мы
put him back in the presidential chair Give him back Give him back
его посадим назад в Президентское кресло
so you Look
Верните его Верните его так вы Смотри
Give us Yanukovych why did you steal
Отдайте нам Янукович зачем вы украли
our Yanukovych I think you should
нашего Януковича я считаю что Вы должны
Why No we should return it Yes we should
Зачем Нет мы должны вернуть Да мы должны
We went to the Kursk region yes in order to
Мы зашли в курскую область да для того
exchange Sudzha for Yanukovych later
чтобы суджу обменять потом на Януковича
And why why can't you find him there
А почему почему никак не найдёте его там
in Sudzha so no So we want Sudzha we
в Судже так нет Так мы хотим суджу мы
want to exchange Sudzha for Yanukovych and
хотим обменять суджу на Януковича а
Putin doesn't want to exchange If it works out to
Путин не хочет менять Если получится
return it That's because you see Putin The
вернуть так Вот потому что видишь Путин
thing is that Putin has a connection with
Дело в том что у Путина есть связь с
Yanukovych Yes and he doesn't want to exchange
Януковичем Да и он не хочет менять
Yanukovych for Sudzha Look And if suddenly it
Януковича на суджу смотрите А если вдруг
doesn't work out to return Sudzha nothing then we
не получится суджи вернуть ничего тогда
will seize Kursk again we will exchange it for
захватим ещё Курск будем менять на
Yanukovych Kursk And if it doesn't work out
Януковича Курск А если не получится
then Orel You  sure yes you are very
тогда Орёл Вы уверены да Вы очень
sure of it very sure And if
уверены в этом очень уверила А если
suddenly it doesn't work out in it Well then
вдруг не получится в этом Ну тогда
Moscow Well then you'll have to Moscow
Москва Ну придётся тогда уже Москву
look And if suddenly it doesn't work out if
смотрите А если вдруг не получится если
you
вас
Booth suddenly look Suddenly you can
Бут вдруг смотри Вдруг это ты можешь
only in short suddenly become smart
только короче вот вдруг стать умным
suddenly you were and became smart but this
вдруг ты был и стал умным но тебе этот
suddenly doesn't shine for you you understand well and here
вдруг не светит понимаешь ну так и тут
oh coup
ой
coup let's
переворот переворот
go letter to y Ista I don't know
поехали пись на й Иста Я не знаю для
why this is for that there to look at the office and
чого це то для то там дивитись на офес а
for that one two or three clicks and you
для теце оди два або три клика а ти
try me and I will be you in me there are a bunch of
тримае мене и я буду ти в мене там Купа
fouls and in me there will be a cool mood to
фолов и в мене буде класний настр щоб
do but cool video letter find Ista pok
робити но крут вдео пись най Иста пок
Andriy
Андрий
so Come on I'm waiting for you
так Давай я тебя чекаю